<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<sect1 id="config-background">
  <title>Fondo</title>
  <para>El fondo es la imagen, el patr贸n o el color que se muestra en el escritorio. Muchas personas lo usan como decoraci贸n para su equipo. El programa <application>Propiedades del fondo</application> configura sus preferencias de fondo.</para>
  <para>Accediendo el <application>Propiedades del fondo</application> puede ser hecho de dos maneras: <itemizedlist>
      <listitem>
        <para>Pulse con el bot贸n secundario del rat贸n en el fondo y luego, con el primario, en <guibutton>Cambiar el fondo del escritorio</guibutton>.</para>
      </listitem>
      <listitem>
        <para>Abriendo el <application>Centro de control de MATE</application> y pulsando dos veces <guibutton>Fondo</guibutton>.</para>
      </listitem>
    </itemizedlist></para>
  <sect2 id="config-background-interface">
    <title>La interfaz de propiedades del fondo</title>
    <para>
      The top of the window shows you a small version of the selected
      background.  Below are boxes which let you select what mode your
      background uses:
      <variablelist>
	<varlistentry>
	  <term>Wallpaper</term>
	  <listitem>
	    <para>
	      Displays your wallpaper in its native form.  You should
	      choose this if your wallpaper is of the exact dimensions
	      of your screen resolution.
	    </para>
	  </listitem>
	</varlistentry>
	<varlistentry>
	  <term>Centered</term>
	  <listitem>
	    <para>
	      Places your image directly in the center of your screen.
	    </para>
	  </listitem>
	</varlistentry>
	<varlistentry>
	  <term>Scaled</term>
	  <listitem>
	    <para>
	      Stretches your image, but keeps the aspect ratio.  This
	      will keep your image from looking funny because it has
	      been stretched too much in one direction.
	    </para>
	  </listitem>
	</varlistentry>
	<varlistentry>
	  <term>Stretched</term>
	  <listitem>
	    <para>
	      Stretches your image to fill your screen, regardless of
	      aspect ratio.  This could distort your images.
	    </para>
	  </listitem>
	</varlistentry>
	<varlistentry>
	  <term>No Picture</term>
	  <listitem>
	    <para>
	      Doesn't use a graphic as the background, but uses colors
	      which are covered below.
	    </para>
	  </listitem>
	</varlistentry>
      </variablelist>
    </para>
    <para>
      Below the said buttons are options to configure the colors.
      These only matter if you selected <guibutton>No
      Picture</guibutton> or your image doesn't fill the whole
      screen.
    </para>
    <para>
      If your image doesn't take up the entire screen, you have the
      option of how to color the outside of it.  You can either choose
      a vertical gradient, horizontal gradient, or a standard solid
      color.  If you choose a solid color, you select the color at
      right by clicking on <guibutton>Color</guibutton>.  If you pick
      a gradient, you will have two options.  Select the colors you
      wish to do and your options will be made automatically.  
    </para>
  </sect2>
  <sect2 id="config-background-settingup">
    <title>Configurar un Fondo</title>
    <para>
      To configure a backgrond, choose one of the following steps:
      <orderedlist numeration="arabic">
	<listitem>
	  <para>
	    Drag and drop an image into the <guibutton>Picture
	    Box</guibutton> or click the button and select the image
	    through the <application>Mate File Selector</application>.
	  </para>
	</listitem>
	<listitem>
	  <para>
	    Select the mode which you wish to use.  Changes are
	    applied automatically, so you can change quickly if you
	    aren't pleased with the results.
	  </para>
	</listitem>
	<listitem>
	  <para>
	    If your image doesn't cover the entire monitor, select
	    your color settings.  Otherwise, you can skip this step.
	  </para>
	</listitem>
	<listitem>
	  <para>
	    Click <guibutton>Close</guibutton> when through with your configuration.
	  </para>
	</listitem>
      </orderedlist>	
    </para>
  </sect2>
</sect1>
